sarahlsmolen@gmail.com | sarahsmo.github.io | 301-471-5946

### **OBJECTIVE**

Hard-working full stack developer with strengths in React JS, JavaScript, HTML, and Node.js. Has had experience working with Agile principles and values, working effectively in a team setting, and having to learn new languages and frameworks quickly on the job.

### **EDUCATION**

### University of Maryland, College Park, MD

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, with a Minor in Statistics Earned May, 2018

# SKILLS & LANGUAGES

#### **Proficient:**

• React JS, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, CSS, HTML, Java, Python, SQL

### **Experience With:**

- Express JS, JQuery, Ajax, Visual Basic, Assembly, C, C#, .NET, Mongo DB, HTTP **Technologies**:
  - Node.js, Git, Android Studio, Service Now, RStudio, Matlab, SAS, MVC Framework

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### Junior Software Engineer, Higher Logic

July 2018 - Present

- Built a navigation sidebar with efficient search functionality and an In-App Help sidebar for assisting customers with site navigation using algorithm and frontend knowledge
- Worked on the small team that built HL's Data Dashboard that uses SQL queries and automated reporting to present customers with their latest aggregated data
- Created new React components for the homepage used daily by client administrators
- Assembled an entire testing library from scratch for HL's React Component Library
- Resolved errors and bugs found in the component library using React JS with Typescript

### Research Assistant, Human-Computer Interaction Lab at UMD

August 2017 - December 2017

- Developed the mobile site for Project Sidewalk using JavaScript and Google Maps API
- Enhanced the overall design of the site by resolving bugs and adding additional features

## **Development Intern, Higher Logic**

June 2017 - August 2017

- Built and deployed a new drag and drop interface for client site customization using JavaScript, C#, and ASP.NET
- Refactored entire codebase in Java to enable language translation of webpages
- Altered the Marketing Automation platform by writing SQL queries

### College Technical Intern, Northrop Grumman

May 2016 - August 2016

- Developed an employee database using HTML and Microsoft Access 2010
- Wrote technical requirements for the Social Security Administration's site redesign